Guide to The Small Pond Magazine Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
The small pond magazine records
1970-1999
YCAL MSS 642
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
6.89
(22 boxes)
The Small Pond Magazine Records contain correspondence, writings, and productions files created in the production of the literary magazine. Correspondence includes letters from contributors to the editor, Napoleon St. Cyr. Writings include works from contributors for review and publication in the magazine. Production files include notes, galleys proofs, photographs, and drawings. The records span the years 1970-1999.
Small pond magazine of literature
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from The Small Pond Magazine on the various funds, 1991-2002.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
The Small Pond Magazine
The Small Pond Magazine was a literary magazine published by Napoleon St. Cyr in Stratford, Connecticut from 1963 to 1999.
Scope and Contents
The Small Pond Magazine Records contain correspondence, writings, and productions files created in the production of the literary magazine. Correspondence includes letters from contributors to the editor, Napoleon St. Cyr. Writings include works from contributors for review and publication in the magazine. Production files include notes, galleys, photographs, and drawings. The records span the years 1970-1999.
Arrangement
Organized into twelve groupings: I. July 1991 Acquisition. II. October 1992 Acquisition. III. December 1993 Acquisition. IV. December 1994 Acquisition. V. November 1995 Acquisition. VI. November 1996 Acquisition. VII. November 1997 Acquisition. VIII. November 1998 Acquisition. IX. November 1999 Acquisition. X. October 2000 Acquisition. XI. December 2001 Acquisition. XII. October 2002 Acquisition.
Small pond magazine of literature; American literature -- 20th Century -- Periodicals; Little magazines -- United States -- 20th Century; Little magazines -- United States; St. Cyr, Napoleon
- July 1991 Acquisition, 1970-1991; 1; 4.17; (11 boxes)
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Purchased from The Small Pond Magazine on the Sinclair Lewis Fund, 1991.
  Arrangement
  Files are arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Contents
  Formerly Uncat ZA MS 203
  - Number 19, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Volume 7, Number 3, Artwork, 1970 Fall (Box 1)
  - Number 19, 1970 Spring (Box 1)
  - Volume 9, Number 2, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Volume 8, Number 1, 1971 Winter; 2 (Box 2)
  - Volume 8, Number 2, 1971 Spring; 2 (Box 2)
  - Volume 8, Number 3, 1971 Fall; 2 (Box 2)
  - Volume 9, Number 1, 1972 Winter; 2 (Box 2)
  - Volume 9, Number 3, 1972 Fall; 2 (Box 2)
  - Volume 10, Number 1, 1973 Winter; 2 (Box 2)
  - 1969 Fall (Box 3)
  - Volume 10, Number 3, 1973 Fall (Box 3)
  - Volume 10, Number 2 (28), 1973 Spring; 2 (Box 3)
  - Volume 10, Number 3, 1973 Fall (Box 3)
  - 1973 November-December (Box 3)
  - 1974 November-January (Box 3)
  - Volume 11, Number 1 (30), 1974 Winter (Box 3)
  - Volume 11, Number 2 (31), 1974 Spring; 2 (Box 3)
  - Volume 11, Number 2 (31), 1974 Fall (Box 3)
  - 1974 December (Box 3)
  - Volume 12, Number 1 (33), 1975 Winter (Box 4)
  - Volume 12, Number 2 (34), 1975 Spring (Box 4)
  - 1975 May (Box 4)
  - Volume 12, Number 3 (35), 1975 Fall; 2 (Box 5)
  - Volume 13, Number 1 (36), 1976 Winter; 2 (Box 5)
  - Volume 13, Number 2 (37), 1976 Spring; 2 (Box 5)
  - Volume 13, Number 3 (38), 1976 Fall; 2 (Box 5)
  - Volume 14, Number 1 (39), 1977 Winter; 2 (Box 5)
  - Volume 14, Number 2 (40), 1977 Spring; 2 (Box 5)
  - Volume 14, Number 3 (41), 1977 Fall; 2 (Box 5)
  - Volume 15, Number 2, 1978 Spring; 2 (Box 6)
  - Volume 15, Number 3 (44), 1978 Fall; 2 (Box 6)
  - Volume 15, Number 1 (42), 1978 Winter (Box 6)
  - Volume 16, Number 2 (46), 1979 Spring; 2 (Box 6)
  - Volume 16, Number 3 (47), 1979 Fall; 2 (Box 6)
  - Volume 16, Number 1 (45), 1979 Winter (Box 6)
  - Volume 17, Number 1 (48), 1980 Winter; 2 (Box 6)
  - Volume 17, Number 2 (49), 1980 Spring; 2 (Box 7)
  - Volume 17, Number 3 (50), 1980 Fall; 2 (Box 7)
  - Volume 18, Number 1 (51), 1981 Winter; 2 (Box 7)
  - Volume 18, Number 2 (52), 1981 Spring; 2 (Box 7)
  - Volume 18, Number 3 (53), 1981 Fall; 2 (Box 7)
  - Volume 19, Number 1 (54), 1982 Winter; 2 (Box 8)
  - Volume 19, Number 3 (56), 1982 Fall; 2 (Box 8)
  - Volume 19, Number 2 (55), 1982 Spring; 2 (Box 8)
  - Volume 20, Number 1 (57), 1983 Winter (Box 8)
  - Volume 20, Number 2 (58), 1983 Spring; 2 (Box 8)
  - Volume 20, Number 3 (59), 1983 Fall; 2 (Box 8)
  - Volume 21, Number 1 (60), 1984 Winter; 2 (Box 9)
  - Volume 21, Number 2 (61), 1984 Spring; 2 (Box 9)
  - Volume 21, Number 3 (62), 1984 Fall; 2 (Box 9)
  - Volume 22, Number 1 (63), 1985 Winter; 2 (Box 9)
  - Volume 22, Number 2 (64), 1985 Spring; 2 (Box 9)
  - Volume 22, Number 3 (65), 1985 Fall (Box 10)
  - Volume 23, Number 1 (66), 1986 Winter; 2 (Box 10)
  - Volume 23, Number 2 (67), 1986 Spring; 2 (Box 10)
  - Volume 23, Number 3 (68), 1986 Fall; 2 (Box 10)
  - Volume 24, Number 1 (69), 1987 Winter; 2 (Box 10)
  - Volume 24, Number 2 (70), 1987 Spring; 2 (Box 10)
  - Volume 24, Number 3 (71), 1987 Fall; 2 (Box 10)
  - Volume 25, Number 1 (72), 1988 Winter; 2 (Box 11)
  - Volume 25, Number 2 (73), 1988 Spring; 2 (Box 11)
  - Volume 25, Number 3 (74), 1988 Fall; 2 (Box 11)
  - Volume 28, Number 2 (82), 1991 Spring (Box 11)
  - Editorial material, 1988-1991 (Box 11)
  - Editorial material, 1983-1984 (Box 11)
- October 1992 Acquisition, 1982-1989; Series II; 0.42; (1 box)
  Purchased from The Small Pond Magazine on the Eugene G. O'Neill Memorial Fund, 1992.
  Formerly Uncat ZA MS 250
  - Editorial lines, 1982-1983 (Box 12)
  - Volume 26, Number 1 (75), 1989 Winter; 2 (Box 12)
  - Volume 26, Number 2 (76), 1989 Spring (Box 12)
  - Volume 26, Number 2 (76), 1989 Spring (Box 12)
  - Volume 26, Number 3 (77), 1989 Fall; 2 (Box 12)
- December 1993 Acquisition, 1990; 3; 0.21; (1 box)
  Purchased from The Small Pond Magazine on the American Literature Fund, Stanton Francis Kennedy Fund, 1993.
  Formerly Uncat ZA MS 309
  - Volume 27, Number 1 (78), 1990 (Box 13)
  - Volume 27, Number 1 (78), 1990 Winter (Box 13)
  - Volume 27, Number 2 (79), 1990 Summer; 2 (Box 13)
  - Volume 27, Number 3 (80), 1990 Fall; 2 (Box 13)
- December 1994 Acquisition, 1991; 4; 0.21; (1 box)
  Purchased from The Small Pond Magazine on the George B. Alvord Fund, 1994.
  Formerly Uncat ZA MS 414
  - Volume 28, Number 1, 1991 Winter; 2 (Box 14)
  - Volume 28, Number 2, 1991 Spring; 2 (Box 14)
  - Volume 28, Number 3, 1991 Fall; 2 (Box 14)
- November 1995 Acquisition, 1992; 5; 0.21; (1 box)
  Purchased from The Small Pond Magazine on the George B. Alvord Fund, 1995.
  Formerly Uncat ZA MS 463
  - Volume 29, Number 1, 1992 Winter (Box 15)
  - Volume 29, Number 1 (reproduction), 1992 Winter (Box 15)
  - Volume 29, Number 2, 1992 Spring (Box 15)
  - Volume 29, Number 2 (reproduction), 1992 Spring (Box 15)
  - Volume 29, Number 3, 1992 Fall (Box 15)
  - Volume 29, Number 3 (reproduction), 1992 Fall (Box 15)
- November 1996 Acquisition, 1993, undated; 6; 0.42; (1 box)
  Purchased from The Small Pond Magazine on the Stanton Francis Kennedy Fund, 1996.
  Formerly Uncat ZA MS 506
  - Volume 30, Number 1 (87), 1993 (Box 16)
  - Volume 30, Number 2 (88), 1993 (Box 16)
  - 87 and 88, 1993 (Box 16)
  - Volume 30, Number 1 (87), 1993 (Box 16)
  - Volume 30, Number 2 (88), 1993; 2 (Box 16)
  - Volume 30, Number 3 (89), 1993 (Box 16)
  - Volume 30, Number 1 (87), 1993 (Box 16)
  - Volume 30, Number 3 (89), 1993 (Box 16)
- November 1997 Acquisition, 1994; 7; 0.21; (1 box)
  Purchased from The Small Pond Magazine on the Bradford F. and Lila L. Swan Fund, 1997.
  Formerly Uncat ZA MS 537
  - Volume 31 (90), 1994 Winter; 2 (Box 17)
  - Volume 31, Number 2 (91), 1994 Spring; 2 (Box 17)
  - Volume 31, Number 3 (92), 1994 Fall; 2 (Box 17)
- November 1998 Acquisition, 1995; 8; 0.21; (1 box)
  Purchased from The Small Pond Magazine on the Bradford F. and Lila L. Swan Fund, 1998.
  Formerly Uncat ZA MS 586
  - Volume 32, Number 1 (93), 1995 Winter (Box 18)
  - Volume 32, Number 2 (94), 1995 Summer (Box 18)
  - Volume 32, Number 3 (95), 1995 Fall (Box 18)
  - Volume 32, Number 1 (93) (reproduction), 1995 Winter (Box 18)
  - Volume 32, Number 2 (94) (reproduction), 1995 Summer (Box 18)
  - Volume 32, Number 3 (95) (reproduction), 1995 Fall (Box 18)
- November 1999 Acquisition, 1996; 9; 0.21; (1 box)
  Purchased from The Small Pond Magazine on the Carl Van Vechten Fund, 1999.
  Formerly Uncat ZA MS 641
  - Number 98, 1996 Fall; 2 (Box 19)
  - Volume 33, Number 1 (96), 1996 Winter; 2 (Box 19)
  - Volume 33, Number 2, 1996 Summer (Box 19)
  - Volume 33, 1996 Summer (Box 19)
- October 2000 Acquisition, 1997; 10; 0.21; (1 box)
  Purchased from The Small Pond Magazine on the Eugene G. O'Neill Memorial Fund, 2000.
  Formerly Uncat MSS 73
  - Volume 34, Number 3 (reproduction), 1997 Summer (Box 20)
  - Volume 34, Number (reproduction), 1997 Fall (Box 20)
  - Volume 34 (99) (reproduction), 1997 Winter (Box 20)
  - Volume 34 (99), 1997 Winter (Box 20)
  - Volume 34, Number 3, 1997 Fall (Box 20)
  - Volume 34, Number 3, 1997 Summer (Box 20)
- December 2001 Acquisition, 1998; 11; 0.21; (1 box)
  Purchased from The Small Pond Magazine on the Martin Greenblatt Foundation Book Fund in American Literature, 2001.
  Formerly Uncat MSS 188
  - Volume 35, 1998 Winter; 2 (Box 21)
  - Volume 35, 1998 Spring (Box 21)
  - Volume 35, 1998 Fall (Box 21)
  - Volume 35 (reproduction), 1998 Fall; 2 (Box 21)
- October 2002 Acquisition, 1999; 12; 0.21; (1 box)
  Purchased from The Small Pond Magazine on the Danford N. Barney, Jr. Fund, 2002.
  Formerly Uncat MSS 378
  - Volume 36, Number 1 (105) (reproduction), 1999 Winter (Box 22)
  - Volume 36, Number 1 (105), 1999 Winter (Box 22)
  - Volume 36, Number 3 (107) (reproduction), 1999 Fall (Box 22)
  - Originals, Volume 36, Number 3 (107), 1999 Fall (Box 22)
  - Originals (106), 1999 Summer (Box 22)
  - Number 2 (106) (reproduction), 1999 Summer (Box 22)